

Programmer Analyst seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, Application Maintenance, Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Solution Architecture, Unix Shell Scripting, Informix, Teradata, SQL Developer, Informatica, Putty, Winscp



Current Designation: Programmer Analyst -Software Total Experience: 6 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Development Highest Degree: MS/M.Sc(Science) [Computers]

Current Company: Cognizant Technology Solutions India Ltd

Current Location: Chennai
Pref. Location: Chennai

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Programmer Analyst, Software Developer, Software Development, Application Programming, Application Maintenance, Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Solution Architecture, Unix Shell Scripting, Informix, Teradata, SQL

Developer, Informatica, Putty, Winscp

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 22-Jan-21 Last Modified: 22-Jan-21

Summary

Having 6.2 years of IT experience in Data Warehousing with expertise in UNIX, Shell scripting, Azure Admin.

Experience in development, maintenance and production support applications in UNIX Shell Scripts.

Experience in working on Global Delivery Model - Onsite/Offshore model

Experience Resource provisioning in both Azure portal and DevOps.

Experience in understanding the user queries and resolving the issues ontime.

Proficiency in production support and problem solving.

Responsible for application availability, ticket resolution, break fixes, Performance tuning, timely implementation of projects and enhancements.

Monitor Knowledge Transition (KT) progress from Application Development team. Created KEDBs and SOPs

Good communication and interpersonal skills and strong understanding of ETL best practices.

Expertise in monitoring and recording the results of executing the quality activities to assess.

Work Experience

Cognizant Technology Solutions India Ltd as Programmer Analyst Jul 2014 to Jul 2014

Cognizant Technology Solutions India Ltd as Programmer Analyst -Software Development Jul 2014 to Till Date

Project Profile 1:

Client Name Walt Disney Parks and Resorts

Project Title Information Advantage Duration 01/08/2015 to 12/1/2020

Location Chennai, India

Operating Systems Unix, Windows

Tools Putty, Informatica 9.x, Teradata 15,16 Cloudera Manager, Uc4, Tws, Winscp,

Project Description: -

ATSR (Automated Ticketing System Reporting) is a data warehouse to store ticketing information generated in the Automated Ticketing System (ATS). Maestro is the scheduling tool for ATSR application.

DTIR (Disney Ticketing Interface Reporting) is a data warehouse that stores transaction data from the DTI system. Maestro is the scheduling tool for DTIR application.

Disney Data Differential (D3) is the Data Hub (front-end collection of data) which made available to the 40 downstream systems and more than 8000 users use it.

Food & Beverage Data Warehouse (FBDW) provides analysis data for all facets of the food and beverage line of business at Walt Disney World. At present, there are approximately 800 Food & Beverage Data Warehouse users.

Client Description:

Disney Parks and Experiences is one of the world?s leading providers of family travel and leisure experiences, with six resort destinations across the globe, including 12 theme parks, 53 resort hotels, a top-rated cruise line and other unique vacation experiences. Through the work of more than 170,000 cast members, the magic of Disney comes to life for families and fans every day around the world.

Roles and Responsibilities in the project: -

Created shell scripts to automate many manual works and Business needs

Hands on experience in SQL with Informix database

Performing functional enhancements to the application and proactive monitoring checks.

Developed Unix Shell script to send the notification mail to users, if the input file is arrived in production server or not. This Script reduces the manual intervention.

Developed Script to get the count of input files and sent mail notification. This Script reduces the manual intervention to check the number of files per day.

Developed Script to automate an application, which will run 24/7 to fix the error while loading the files. With the help of script, it will fix around 800+ errors/day.

Work closely with Business Analysts and Application Users for Requirements Gathering, User Acceptance Testing etc. Coordinate with various teams at client site such as Business Intelligence Reporting, Infrastructure, Upstream applications and downstream applications teams for smoother deployment and issue resolution in QA and Production environments. Involved in analyzing, resolving and providing fix for all the production critical issues.

Provide support for operational activities including job scheduling, failure investigation, dependencies, job monitoring and maintenance.

Closely monitor and coordinate with various Upstream and Downstream team.

Participate in meetings with client to report project status, issues and resolution.

Project Profile 2:

Client Name T-Mobile Project Title **EDS T-Mobile** Duration 3/3/2020 - Till Date Location Chennai, India Operating Systems UNIX, Windows Platform Microsoft Azure

Project Description: -

T-Mobile is having 55 applications hosted in Azure platform. Like marketing, retail, finance and so on T-Mobile started to move applications to cloud Platform from Jan 2019 onwards. Application created in Azure Platform for higher availability, stability and pay as you go model.

Roles and Responsibilities in the project: -

Actively involved in monitoring the ticketing tool and resolved the issue depends on the priority.

Involved in planning and execution of resource provisioning.

Responsibilities to understand Client Processes and to work efficiently to meet targets and deliver solutions in accordance with Cognizant quality control standards.

Further responsibilities also comprise of ensuring top quality deliverable from Cognizant to client and collection of project met

as Programmer Analyst Jul 2014 to Jul 2014

Education

UG: B.Sc (information system management) from JBAS college for women, Chennai in 2014

PG: MS/M.Sc(Science) (Computers) from University of Madras in 2017

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
Unix shell scripting	
Informix, Teradata	
Putty, WinSCP, SQL Developer	
Service Now, Atomic, TWS	
Ms Office 2000 / 2003	
Informatica 9.x	

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Tamil				

Affirmative Action

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time